Preliminary Guide to the Pierpont's Store Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Pierpont's Store records
1820-1884
MS 399
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
Sixty-four volumes of accounts, 1850-1884, of Pierpont's Store in North Haven, Connecticut. Also included are 161 loose papers: 13 of these were removed from the account books; the remaining 148, Sept. 1854-Sept. 1857, are mainly authorizations by various doctors for sale by Pierpont's Store of liquor for medicinal uses.
Pierpont's Store
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the account books of Rufus Pierpont, 1818-1855, and his wife Harriet Pierpont. They ran a general store in North Haven, Connecticut, dealing in dry goods as well as foodstuffs and liquors.
See also the Pierpont Family Papers, MS 1125. That collection includes some 1847 bills of Rufus Pierpont and a church resolution on his death.
Biographical / Historical
This grocery and general store was founded in 1848 by Rufus Pierpont (b. 1818), who managed it until his death in 1855. He was Husband of Harriet R. Peirpont; father of Daniel Hobart Pierpont (a graduate of the Yale Sheffield Scientific School, 1871). Only brother of Elias Pierpont of New Haven. Proprietor of Pierpont's Store in New Haven. Member of St. Johns's Protestant Episcopal Church, North Haven, Conn. Died July 31, 1855.
It was taken over by Harriet R. Pierpont, his wife, who appears to have been the proprietor for the remainder of the period of these accounts. The store remained in the family until it was forced to close in 1942, at which time it was the second oldest business institution in North Haven.
Business; General stores; Connecticut; North Haven (Conn.); Account books; Pierpont's Store
- Inventory
  - Day books
    - 1862 Jul-Sep (Box 1)
    - 1863 Jun-1865 Mar (Box 1)
    - 1865 Jun-1866 Jun (Box 1)
    - 1866 Jun-1868 Jun (Box 2)
    - 1868 Jun-1870 Nov (Box 3)
    - 1870 Nov-1873 Jul (Box 4)
    - 1873 Sep-1875 Jul (Box 5)
    - 1875 Jul-1877 Jan, with some entries to 1884 (Box 6)
  - Ledgers
    - 1853-1856 (Box 7)
    - 1854-1858 (Box 7)
    - 1855-1862, including an account with the estate of Rufus Pierpont (Box 8)
    - 1857-1864, with some day book entries (Box 8)
    - 1861-1869, with some day book entries (Box 8)
    - 1861-1868 (Box 8)
    - 1865-1877 (Box 8)
    - 1867-1877 (Box 9)
    - 1871-1877 (Box 9)
  - Account books
    - 1837-1858 (Box 9)
    - 1850-1859 (Box 9)
    - 1860-1876 (Box 9)
    - Accounts of liquor purchases and sales, 1854-1857 (Box 9)
    - 1865-1876 (Box 10)
    - 1869-1880 (Box 10)
  - Loose papers
    - 1854 Sep-1857 Sep (Box 10)
    - Undated, and printed matter (Box 10)